[
  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is a scale made up of?",
    "incorrect": [
      "Semicones and Cones",
      "Semilones and Lones",
      "Semiphones and Phones"
    ],
    "correct": "Semitones and Tones"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is a semitone?",
    "incorrect": [
      "A quarter step",
      "Two whole steps",
      "A whole step"
    ],
    "correct": "A half step"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is a tone?",
    "incorrect": [
      "A quarter step",
      "Two whole steps",
      "A half step"
    ],
    "correct": "A whole step"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "How can a major scale be written with tones and semitones?",
    "incorrect": [
      "Semitone, Semitone, Semitone, Tone, Tone, Tone, Semitone",
      "Tone, Tone, Tone, Tone, Semitone, Tone, Semitone",
      "Semitone, Semitone, Tone, Semitone, Semitone, Semitone, Tone"
    ],
    "correct": "Tone, Tone, Semitone, Tone, Tone, Tone, Semitone"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What many sharps or flats does the C major scale have?",
    "incorrect": [
      "0 Sharps and 1 Flat",
      "1 Sharp and 0 Flats",
      "1 Sharp and 1 Flat"
    ],
    "correct": "0 Sharps or Flats"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What many sharps does the G major scale have?",
    "incorrect": [
      "0 Sharps",
      "2 Sharps",
      "3 Sharps"
    ],
    "correct": "1 Sharp"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What many sharps does the D major scale have?",
    "incorrect": [
      "0 Sharps",
      "1 Sharps",
      "3 Sharps"
    ],
    "correct": "2 Sharps"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What many flats does the F major scale have?",
    "incorrect": [
      "0 Flats",
      "2 Flats",
      "3 Flats"
    ],
    "correct": "1 Flat"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What sharps does the G major scale have?",
    "incorrect": [
      "F# and C#",
      "G#",
      "D#"
    ],
    "correct": "F#"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What sharps does the D major scale have?",
    "incorrect": [
      "D# and C#",
      "F# and D#",
      "D#"
    ],
    "correct": "F# and C#"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What flats does the F major scale have?",
    "incorrect": [
      "D♭",
      "F♭ and B♭",
      "F♭"
    ],
    "correct": "B♭"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What note does the C major scale start on?",
    "incorrect": [
      "G",
      "E",
      "D"
    ],
    "correct": "C"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What note does the G major scale start on?",
    "incorrect": [
      "C",
      "F#",
      "D"
    ],
    "correct": "G"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What note does the D major scale start on?",
    "incorrect": [
      "C#",
      "F#",
      "G"
    ],
    "correct": "D"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What note does the F major scale start on?",
    "incorrect": [
      "D",
      "B♭",
      "C"
    ],
    "correct": "F"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is a major tonic triad made up of?",
    "incorrect": [
      "The Second (2), The Third (3), The Fifth (5)",
      "The Tonic (1), The Third (3), The Fourth (4)",
      "The Tonic (1), The Second (2), The Fifth (5)"
    ],
    "correct": "The Tonic (1), The Third (3), The Fifth (5)"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is the C major tonic triad made up of?",
    "incorrect": [
      "G, B, D",
      "C, E, F",
      "C, F, G"
    ],
    "correct": "C, E, G"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is the G major tonic triad made up of?",
    "incorrect": [
      "D, F#, A",
      "G, E, F",
      "G, C, D"
    ],
    "correct": "G, B, D"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is the D major tonic triad made up of?",
    "incorrect": [
      "F, A, C",
      "G, B, D",
      "D, G, A"
    ],
    "correct": "D, F#, A"
  },

  {
    "grade": 1,
    "category": "scales",
    "question": "What is the F major tonic triad made up of?",
    "incorrect": [
      "D, F#, A",
      "C, E, G",
      "F, B♭, C"
    ],
    "correct": "F, A, C"
  }
]
